list.ly 2019-06-24

# Privacy Policy - Listly

Last Updated: May 25, 2018

Our Privacy Policy explains how Listly collects, uses, and discloses information about you. The terms “Listly,” "we," "us," and "our" include TwtPickin Inc. and our affiliates. We use the terms “user,” “you,” and “your” to mean any person using our website and associated tools (“Platform”), including any organization or person using the Platform on an organization’s behalf.  This Privacy Policy applies to the processing of information about users and other individuals that we collect when you use our Platform, or services we offer, or when you communicate with us. For information about choices that we offer under this policy, please see “Your Choices” below. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the information that you may provide to third parties, such as users, and others with whom you may share information about yourself.

### 1\. Information We Collect And Receive

Listly may collect and receive Customer Data and other information and data (“Other”) in a variety of ways.  Certain visitors to Listly and websites with embedded Listly lists choose to interact with the lists in ways that require Listly to gather personally-identifying information.  The amount and type of information that Listly gathers depends on the nature of your interaction.

#### 1.1 Information You Provide To Us

We ask users who sign up to Listly to provide a username and email address.  If you use your Facebook, Twitter, or other social networking site (‘SNS’) account information to sign in to Listly, we will collect and store your SNS user ID and related information.  Users that purchase a paid version of the Platform provide Listly (or its payment processors) with billing details such as credit card information, banking information and/or a billing address

#### 1.2 Information We Collect Automatically When You Use the Platform

Platform Content. You may also create a public or private list on Listly, contribute to someone else’s list by voting, commenting, and adding items. These contributions are publicly viewable on Listly, along with their name.  This information may be searched by search engine and republished elsewhere on the Web.

Platform Metadata. When an authorized user interacts with the Platform, metadata is generated that provides additional context about the way you interact with the Platform content and other users. For example, Listly logs the lists you visit, people you follow, content and links you interact with, the content you shared, and what third party services are used (if any).

Log Data. As with most websites and technology services delivered over the Internet, our servers automatically collect information when you access or use our Websites or Services and record it in log files. This log data may include the Internet Protocol (IP) address, the address of the web page visited before using the Website or Services, browser type and settings, the date and time the Services were used, information about browser configuration and plugins, language preferences and cookie data

Device Information. We collect information about the computer or mobile device that you use to access our Platform, including the hardware model, operating system and version, unique device identifiers, and mobile network information.

Location information. We receive information from you or other third-parties that helps us approximate your location. We may, for example, an IP address received from your browser or device to determine approximate location. Listly may also collect location information from devices in accordance with the consent process provided by your device. This helps us customize the site content based on your approximate location.

Information Collected by Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies. We and our service providers collect information using various technologies, including cookies and pixel tags (which are also called clear GIFs, web beacons, or pixels). Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive or in device memory that help us improve our Platform and your experience, and track usage of our Platform. Pixel tags are electronic images that may be used in our Platform or emails, and track usage of our Platform and effectiveness of communications. You can learn more about the types of cookies we and our service providers use by reading our [Cookie Policy](https://list.ly/cookie-policy/).

#### 1.3 Information We Collect From Other Sources

We may collect information about you from other sources, such as through certain features on the Platform you elect to use, but only where these third parties either have your consent or are otherwise legally permitted or required to disclose your information to us. Examples include:

Social Media Services. If you register or log into your account through a third-party social media service, we will have access to some of your third-party account information from that service, such as your name and other information in that account, and used for purposes such as improving your Listly recommendations. We may also have access to third-party account information if you use the Platform feature to share a link.

Invitations. If another user sends you an invitation through our Platform, we may receive certain personal information, such as your name, email address, or phone number. If you are an invited guest, we will automatically send you an invitation to our Platform, and, if unanswered, a one-time follow-up invitation. Listly stores this contact information only to send these invitations and evaluate their success. You may unsubscribe from future invitations using the instructions in those messages. You may also contact us at privacy@list.ly to request that we remove this information from our database.

User Content. We may receive information about you when you or another user uploads photos or posts other content to the Platform. For further details about the rights over this information available to individuals, see Section 6.

### 2\. Use Of Information

We use information about you to:

  * Operate, improve, promote, and protect Listly Platform
  * Communicate with you, and
  * Personalize content.

#### 2.1 Operating our Platform

We may use information about you for various purposes related to operating our Platform, including to:

  * Provide, maintain, and improve our Platform, including to process transactions, develop new products and services, and manage the performance of our Platform;
  * Display information about you, for instance, your profile image, username, etc, which will be visible on your profile;
  * Personalize the Platform, for example, to suggest content in which we think you may be interested or people that you might be interested in connecting with on Listly
  * Allow you to share information about your use of the Platform through a third-party social media service, if you connect your account through that service (which you can turn off at any time) and to provide you with better recommendations;
  * Monitor and analyze trends, usage, and activities in connection with our Platform; and
  * Detect, investigate, and prevent fraudulent transactions, abuse, and other illegal activities; to protect the rights, property, or safety of Listly and others; to enforce compliance with our policies; and to comply with applicable law and government requests.
  * Perform accounting and administrative tasks, and enforce or manage legal claims.

#### 2.2 Communicating With You

We may use information about you for various purposes related to communicating with you, including to:

  * Respond to your comments, questions, and requests, and provide customer service;
  * Communicate with you, in accordance with your account settings, about products, services, and content offered by us and other users, to provide news and information that we think will be of interest to you, to conduct online surveys, and to otherwise communicate with you in accordance with Section 2.3;
  * Notify you about communications of other users, in accordance with the communication preferences that you indicate in your account; and
  * Send you technical notices, updates, security alerts and support, and administrative messages.

#### 2.3 Advertising And Other Uses

We may use information about you for various other purposes, including to:

  * Provide content, features, or products that match user profiles or interests;
  * Facilitate contests and other promotions;
  * Combine with information that we collect for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy; and
  * Carry out any other purposes described to you at the time that we collected the information.

#### 2.4 Legal Basis for Processing

Our legal basis for collecting and using the information described above will depend on the type of information and the specific context in which we collect it.

  * We process information about you in order to provide our services in accordance with our [Terms of Service](https://list.ly/terms/), for example to allow you to make lists, follow users, or to display your profile to other users, and to allow us to send you important service updates.
  * We also process information about you where it is in our legitimate interests to do so and not overridden by your rights (for example, in some cases for direct marketing, fraud prevention, network and information systems security, responding to your communications, the operation of networks of groups by the network administrators, and improving our Platform).
  * Sometimes you provide us with sensitive information about you; for instance, the mere fact of creating or viewing content on a specific topic may indicate information about your health, religion, political views, or sexual identity. Creating and viewing content, or posting content or comments on the Platform about these topics is entirely voluntarily and done with your explicit consent.
  * In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect information about you, or may otherwise need the information to protect your vital interests or those of another person.
  * We may also process information to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contract.

### 3\. Sharing Of Information

#### 3.1 Through Our Platform

We share some of the information that we collect by displaying it on our Platform according to your user profile and account settings. Some information, such as user name, is always public. Some information, such as interests, is public by default, but can be hidden on our Platform. Some information, such as your contributions to other users content will always be visible publicly depending on the settings for that list.

#### 3.2 With Our Service Providers

We may use service providers in connection with operating and improving the Platform to assist with certain functions, such as payment processing, email transmission, conducting surveys or contests, data hosting, managing our ads, and some aspects of our technical and customer support. We take measures to ensure that these service providers access, process, and store information about you only for the purposes we authorize, subject to confidentiality obligations.

#### 3.3 Following The Law And Protecting Listly

We may access, preserve, and disclose information about you to third parties, including the content of messages, if we believe disclosure is in accordance with, or required by, applicable law, regulation, legal process, or audits. We may also disclose information about you if we believe that your actions are inconsistent with our [Terms of Service](https://list.ly/terms/) or related guidelines and policies, or if necessary to protect the rights, property, or safety of, or prevent fraud or abuse of, Listly or others.

#### 3.4 Social Sharing And Other Tools

The Platform may offer social sharing features and other integrated tools which let you share actions that you take on our Platform with third-party services, and vice versa. Such features let you share information with your friends or the public, depending on the settings you have chosen with the service. The third-party services' use of the information will be governed by the third-parties’ privacy policies, and we do not control the third-parties’ use of the shared data. For more information about the purpose and scope of data collection and processing in connection with social sharing features, please review the privacy policies of the services that provide these features.

#### 3.5 Affiliate Sharing And Merger, Sale, Or Other Asset Transfers

If Listly is involved in a merger, acquisition, financing, reorganization, bankruptcy, or sale of our assets, information about you may be shared, sold, or transferred as part of that transaction. We may also share information about you with current or future corporate parents, subsidiaries, or affiliates.

#### 3.6 Other Situations

We may de-identify or aggregate information about you and share it freely, so that you can no longer be identified. We may also share information about you with your consent or at your direction or where we are legally entitled to do so.

### 4\. Additional Details

#### 4.1 Analytics and Advertising Services Provided by Others

With your permission, we may allow others to use cookies, web beacons, device identifiers, and other technologies to collect information about your use of the Platform and other websites and online services. See our [Cookie Policy](https://list.ly/cookie-policy/) for details about these technologies and the information that they collect, use, or share, including how you may be able to control or disable these services.

#### 4.2 Transfer Of Information To The U.S. And Other Countries

Listly is based in the United States. Information about you will be transferred to, and processed in, the U.S. and countries other than the country in which you are resident. These countries may have data protection laws that are different to the laws of your country and, in some cases, may not be as protective. We have taken appropriate safeguards to require that your information will remain protected in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

#### 4.3 Security

We employ technical and organizational measures designed to appropriately protect your information that is under our control and that we process on your behalf from unauthorized access collection, use, disclosure, copying, modification or disposal, both during transmission and once we receive it. We store all information that you provide to us on secure servers. We train employees regarding our data privacy policies and procedures, and permit authorized employees to access information on a need to know basis, as required for their role. We use firewalls designed to protect against intruders and test for network vulnerabilities. However, no method of transmission over the internet or method of electronic storage is completely secure.

Where you have a password, which enables you to use our services, you are responsible for keeping this password complex, secure, and confidential. If you would like to update or change your password, you may select the “Forgot your password?” link on the login page. You will be sent an email that allows you to reset your password.

#### 4.4 Data Retention

We may temporarily block your account if you have not logged in for twelve months or more. You may contact us if you wish to reactivate your account. We retain certain information that we collect from you while you are a user of the Platform, and in certain cases where you have deleted your account, for the following reasons:

  * So you can use our Platform;
  * So ensure that we do not communicate with you if you have asked us not to;
  * To provide you with a refund, if entitled;
  * To better understand the traffic to our Platform so that we can provide all users with the best possible experience;
  * To detect and prevent abuse of our Platform, illegal activities and breaches of our Terms of Service; and
  * To comply with applicable legal, tax or accounting requirements.

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your information, we will either delete or anonymize it.

#### 4.5 Policy Scope

This Privacy Policy does not apply to information that you provide to third parties, such as other users with whom you may share information about you. Our Platform may direct you to a third-party service, such as social media services, or a portion of our Platform may be controlled by a third party (typically through embedded content). Disclosure of information to these third parties is subject to the relevant third party’s privacy policy. We are not responsible for the third-party privacy policy or content, even if we link to those services from our Platform

#### 4.6 Revisions To This Policy

We may modify this Privacy Policy from time to time. When we do, we will provide notice to you by publishing the most current version and revising the date at the top of this page. If we make any material change to this policy, we will provide additional notice to you, such as by sending you an email or displaying a prominent notice on our Platform.

### 5\. Your Choices

#### 5.1 Your Choices: Account Information

You may update or correct your account information by editing your account settings or by sending a request to privacy@list.ly as described in Section 6. You may deactivate your account by editing your account settings or by sending an email to privacy@list.ly.

#### 5.2 Your Choices: Location Information

When you first access the Platform, we will collect information about your location, which we use to make better recommendations for content relevant to where you live or create local lists that look for places around you to add to lists. If you do not want us to collect information about your location, then you can prevent this:

  * If using a mobile app, by changing the settings on your device.
  * If using our website, your location data will be obtained via a cookie. Please refer to our [Cookie Policy](https://list.ly/cookie-policy/) for additional information on how to manage our use of cookies.

Note that our Platform or its features may no longer function properly if you do.

Your mobile device settings may also give you the option to choose whether to allow us to view your location on a continuous basis, when only using the app, or never. Allowing us to view your location when you are not using the app allows us to provide you with recommendations on a regular basis. Please refer to your device’s guide for additional information on how to adjust location services.

#### 5.3 Your Choices: Cookies

We may use and allow others to use cookies, web beacons, device identifiers, and other technologies to collect information about your use of the Platform and other websites and online services. See our [Cookie Policy](https://list.ly/cookie-policy/) for details about these technologies and the information that they collect, use, or share, including how you may be able to control or disable these services.

#### 5.4 Your Choices: Promotional Communications

You can control messages that you receive from Listly by selecting the unsubscribe link in the message that you receive, or by adjusting the communication preferences in your account settings. We will also send you a link to these settings when you first sign up and in subsequent messages. You can opt-out of different types of transactional emails, newsletters, promotional emails or even choose to unsubscribe from all Listly emails.

### 6\. Data Rights

Rights that you may have, depending on the country in which you live, include:

  * Accessing, correcting, updating, or requesting deletion of your information.
  * Objecting to processing of your information, asking us to restrict processing of your information, or requesting the portability of your information.
  * Opting out from receiving marketing communications that we send you at any time. You can exercise this right by selecting the “unsubscribe” or “opt-out” link in the marketing emails we send you. Additionally, you may update your email preferences by changing the settings in your account.
  * Withdrawing your consent at any time if we have collected and processed your information with your consent. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing that we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.
  * Complaining to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your information. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority. Contact details for data protection authorities in the European Union are available [here](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm).

### 7\. Ads

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Listly and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.  For reference, please read our [Cookie Policy](https://list.ly/cookie-policy/).

### 8\. Contact Us

If you have any questions or complaints about this Privacy Policy or how we use your information, please contact privacy@list.ly.
